hovrs.com 2015-06-08

# Purple Communications

Purple Communications, Inc. (“Purple”) developed the following privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to privacy on the Internet. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for [http://purple.us](http://purple.us/) and all other websites owned and operated by Purple. You can contact Purple at:

### By mail:

Attention: Legal Department  
Purple Communications, Inc.  
595 Menlo Drive  
Rocklin, CA 95765  
USA

### By phone:

(800)-900-9478 Ext. 6914

### Collection of Personal Information from Site Visitors

Purple may collect and/or track 1), home server domain names, email addresses, type of client computer and type of visitor Web browsers to Purple’s website, 2) email addresses of visitors communicating with Purple via email, 3) information knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms, surveys and contest entries (including demographic and personal profile data), and 4) aggregate and user-specific information on pages Purple Website visitor access.

Purple may place Internet “cookies” on visitors’ hard drives. Internet cookies save data about individual visitors, such as visitor name, password, username, shopping cart, screen preferences, pages of a site viewed by the visitor, and the advertisements viewed or clicked by the visitor. When the visitor revisits Purple’s website, Purple may recognize the visitor by the Internet cookie and customize the visitor’s experience accordingly. Visitors may decline Internet cookies, if any, by using the appropriate feature of their web client software, if available. When a visitor performs a search within Purple’s website, Purple may record information identifying the visitor or linking the visitor to the search performed. Purple may also record limited information for every search request and use that information to solve technical problems with service, as well as calculate overall usage statistics.

### Use of Personal Data Collected

Personal data collected by Purple may be used by Purple for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes (unless you choose to opt-out as outlined below), for a statistical analysis of user behavior, for product development, for content improvement, to inform advertisers of how many visitors have seen or clicked on their advertisements or to customize the content and layout of Purple’s site. Aggregate data on visitor home servers may be used for internal purposes or provided to third parties, such as advertisers. Individually identifying information, such as names, postal and email addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information which visitors voluntarily provide to Purple may be i) added to Purple’s databases and used for future calls and mailings regarding site updates, new products and services, upcoming events, and status of orders placed online, or ii) provided to reputable third parties who provide products and services which Purple believes that visitors may be interested in purchasing or obtaining, with prior notice to the visitor.

### Disclosure of Personal Data to Third Parties

Any third party to which Purple shares, rents, sells or otherwise discloses personal data will be under a contractual obligation to use the personal data for marketing products and services which Purple determines, in its sole judgment, that visitors might find of interest. Purple will use its reasonable efforts to identify such third parties who may have products or services of interest to visitors to Purple’s site; however, such parties are independent third parties over which Purple exercises no control, and therefore, Purple is not responsible for their conduct, products or services, and will not be liable therefore. Purple will disclose to third parties only information in aggregate form that is publicly available, and/or that is knowingly and voluntarily disclosed by visitors. If there are advertisements on Purple’s website, the advertiser(s) will be electronically notified when visitors view or click on their advertisements through the use of third party cookies.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act Notice

Purple does not track consumer online activities over time and across third-party Web sites and therefore does not use "do not track" signals.

Purple does not authorize the collection of personally identifiable information by third parties about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across different Web sites when a consumer uses the Purple Web site or service. 

### Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI)

Customer Proprietary Network Information (CPNI) is information that Purple and other relay providers obtain when providing customers with relay service.  CPNI includes the types of relay a customer uses, the amount of relay calls made, and the location of those calls. 

### Use of CPNI

Purple and its affiliates may access CPNI to provide you with relay service, to process 911 calls, for installation, maintenance and repair services, and to offer you additional services of the type you already registered for with Purple and its affiliates.  Purple and its affiliates may also use your CPNI to offer you products and services which may be different from the types of services you already use.  Purple asks for your consent to do this during your registration process.  At any time you may choose to opt out of this use of your CPNI for marketing purposes.

### Restricting Use of CPNI

Customers have the right to deny any TRS providers the right to use, disclose or permit access to customer CPNI for certain marketing purposes, and TRS providers have a duty under federal law to honor the customer’s right and to protect the confidentiality of CPNI.

If you wish to restrict Purple’s use of your CPNI for marketing purposes, you may do the following:

1.Login at www.purple.us;

2.Go to the Email & Password section of your User Profile; and

3.Uncheck the CPNI Opt-in checkbox.

Alternatively, you may contact Purple Customer Care at 877-885-3172.

Your approval or denial for use of CPNI for these marketing purposes will not affect Purple’s provision of relay services to you.  However, the lack of access to CPNI may prohibit Purple and its affiliates from offering you new and different services that may be of interest to you and tailored to your relay needs.

Your approval or denial for use of CPNI outside of the service for which Purple and its affiliates are your default provider will stay in place until you change it.

### Security Measures

Purple has implemented various security features to prevent the unauthorized release of, or access to, personal information. In particular, when a visitor places an order on this site (if any) or accesses his or her account information (if any), Purple offers the visitor the ability to use a secure server. The secure server encrypts all information a visitor inputs before it is sent to Purple, and is also used to securely store personal information. Please be advised, however, that while Purple has endeavored to create a secure and reliable site for visitors, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from Purple via this site or email cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, Purple is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. For a more secure and private communication, visitors can contact us by telephone at (800)-900-9478.

### Opt-Out Right

Visitors may opt out of having their personal information collected by Purple, used by Purple for secondary purposes, disclosed to third parties, or used by Purple or third parties to send promotional correspondences to the visitor by contacting Purple via postal mail, email or telephone, or by checking the appropriate box.

### Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

Upon request via postal mail, email or phone, Purple will provide to visitors a summary of any personal information retained by Purple regarding the visitor. Visitors may modify, correct, change or update their personal record or cause their personal record to be removed from Purple’s database. Purple will only send personal records to the email address on file for the associated visitor name.

### Collection of Personal Data from Children

To the extent Purple is able to determine the age of users by their submissions to, or communications with, Purple’s website, Purple will not knowingly i) collect or post information from individuals under the age of sixteen (“children”) without parent or guardian consent, or ii) provide any personally identifying information collected from children, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever. If registration is required for any services on the Purple website, and a user submits information to Purple’s website as part of the registration process which indicates that such user is a child, the child’s parent or guardian will receive an email alerting them to the child’s registration and providing instructions on how the parent can delete the child’s registration, if so desired. No information collected through Purple’s website from users self-identified as children will knowingly be used for any marketing or promotional purposes whatsoever, either inside or outside of Purple. If there are no age restrictions on a contest which requires registration, and if a child wins, notification and prizes will be sent to the parent or guardian identified in the initial registration process.

### Purple’s Right to Contact User

Purple reserves the right to contact site visitors regarding account status and changes to the subscriber agreement, privacy policy, or any other policies or agreements relevant to site visitors.

### Purple’s Right to Change Privacy Policy

The foregoing policy is effective as of April 2014. Purple reserves the right to change this policy at any time by notifying visitors of the existence and location of the new or revised privacy policy. By entering the Purple website, you are accepting all terms and conditions outlined in the above Purple Privacy Policy
